<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-1.0.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <title>Maven Erlang Plug-In Release Notes</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <release version="2.1.0" date="TBA" description="Feature and bugfix release">
      <action dev="olle-t" type="fix">
        Enhanced compilation to check for exported "parse_transform/2" and sort
        those modules to the top of the compilation list. Resolves compilation
        dependencies issues.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, lti" type="fix">
        Backend nodes will now be started in fully qualified hostname mode
        (-name) using one of the IPv4 addresses configured on the host machine.
        This fixes problems with backend node connectivity in certain
        environments, e.g. problems experienced on MacOS X or in networks
        without running DNS services. In case reading the IP addresses from the
        network interfaces fails the old behaviour (-name bla@localhost) is
        used.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Provided an alternative for the ERL_FLAGS environment variable for
        target systems. This variable is useful when different releases (nodes)
        should be run on the same host.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="update">
        Projects will now be run with dependencies by default when running an
        application in remote mode.
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t, schlagert" type="fix">
        Fixed false test runner results when executing tests containing test
        generators.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="update">
        Changed mojo logging to be more intuitive when displaying warnings and
        errors.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Modules defining custom behaviours will now be compiled. This avoids
        warnings emitted when behaviours can't be found. 
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        Added 'erlang:profile' and 'erlang:profiling-report' - eprof based 
        profiling and reporting, using the tests in an application project.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added 'erlang:relup' to generate sensible release upgrade file
        templates based on installed/deployed versions of a project. 
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added 'erlang:appup' to generate sensible application upgrade file
        templates based on installed/deployed versions of a project. 
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="fix" issue="3240436">
        Fixed packaging problems where the wrong version string was used to
        for comparison when validating and checking dependencies.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="fix" issue="3240233">
        Fixed packaging problems of release projects when the backend node has
        several OTP installations in its library directory. Standard OTP
        application dependencies will now be searched for in the code path of
        the current backend node.
      </action>
    </release>    
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2011-03-18" description="First stable release">
      <action dev="ghaskins" type="add" issue="3167277">
        Added tool 'eapp2mvn' to deploy non-maven packaged erlang applications
        to a maven repository using configurable coordinates.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="add">
        Added generated help mojo 'erlang:help' to display information about the
        available goals.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, heyll" type="remove">
        Removed the 'failIfNoTests' parameter for simplifying plug-ing usage.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="fix">
        Fixed dangling application project dependencies in 'target/lib' when
        changing a dependency version and not 'cleaning' the next build. 
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="update">
        Made 'relup' and 'sys.config' files mandatory in erlang-rel projects.
        Added basic template generation for those in 'erlang:setup'.
      </action>
      <action dev="heyll" type="add">
        Added the 'erlang:show-build-info' goal that outputs code paths and 
        include paths used to compile the erlang sources, so that other tools
        (i.e. emacs) can compile erlang files of a mavenized erlang project. 
      </action>
      <action dev="ghaskins" type="add">
        Added UnArchiver support to erlang-rel artifacts. This allows other
        projects to consume these artifacts, e.g. rpm-maven-plugin based
        artifacts.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="remove">
        Removed built-in mock library support. Use external library instead.
        E.g. 'erlymock' by Sven Heyll (https://github.com/sheyll/erlymock).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added experimental goal to create a startable target system from a
        release project (according to the official erlang documentation).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="update">
        Changed semantics of the ${ERTS} release packaging variables to expand
        to the complete erts version tuple as required by the release file's
        erts section.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added goal erlang:upload to upload the applications and releases to a
        remote erlang node (located on another machine).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="update">
        Changed semantics of the ${APPLICATION_NAME} release packaging
        variables to expand to the complete application name, version tuple as
        required by the release file's applications section.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="update" issue="3166835">
        Changed semantics of ${APPLICATIONS} for erlang-otp/erlang-std projects.
        This will now expand to a comma separated listing instead of an erlang
        list.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="update" >
        Release and release upgrade files of erlang-rel projects must now be of
        the form [ARTIFACTID].rel / [ARTIFACTID].relup. This allows usage of the
        maven-release-plugin that changes the effective project version in the
        pom while building. Though, generated release artifacts will retain the
        version information in the filenames.  
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="fix" issue="3166359" due-to="ghaskins">
        Added support to recognise both British and American spelling of the
        -behaviour tag.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="update" issue="3166835" due-to="ghaskins">
        Refined dependency management of releases by choosing the standard
        erlang/OTP application versions from a specific OTP release.
        Availability of the required release is checked (but may be skipped for
        testing purposes).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="update" issue="3166182" due-to="ghaskins">
        Improved application packaging by adding the customizable ${APPLICATIONS}
        packaging variable which expands to all application dependencies (except
        OTP standard ones).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="update" issue="3165497" due-to="ghaskins">
        Improved release packaging by adding the customizable ${AUTODEPS}
        packaging variable which expands to all release dependencies (including
        OTP standard ones).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="update" issue="3165497" due-to="ghaskins">
        Changed the ${APPLICATIONS} release packaging variable to expand to a
        comma separated listing of all release dependencies (including OTP
        standard ones).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="update">
        Introduced two backend nodes. One used for testing and another one for
        compiling, packaging, running projects.
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        Added plain text coverage report as optional output direct to stdout
        instead of saved coverage report.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="remove">
        Removed support for SNMP resource compilation.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="remove">
        Main and test resources no longer supported by packaging, replaced with
        main and test priv directories (can be found using code:priv_dir/1).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added support for test and provided scope dependencies.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Fixed run goal erlang:run to start all transitive application
        dependencies and pre-load all project (and dependency) modules. The goal
        can now run projects on remote nodes (located on another machine).
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added more checks for release file management support, removed automatic
        release file generation.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added more checks for application file management support, removed
        automatic application file generation.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added several unit and integration tests.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, olle-t" type="add">
        All mojos now use jinterface for erlang rpcs instead of using
        erl -run or erl -eval. First of all this speeds up the build
        significantly. Another big advantage is that the plugin can now be
        integrated into the development using emacs with the distel extension
        since the plugin can use the emacs distel node or vice versa.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added packaging type erlang-std which respects the default erlang/OTP
        application directory layout.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Test suffixes can now be either "_test" (for backward compatibility) or
        "_tests" eunit standard.
      </action>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0-beta" date="2010-12-17" description="Initial release">
      <action dev="olle-t" type="update">
        Changed the use of the "test" property, a single specified test 
        (-Dtest=some_test) is always considered to have a .beam suffix, but
        never assumes anything else about the test module name. 
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        New mojo that copies test-resources, bound to the 
        generate-test-resources phase. 
      </action>
      <action dev="heyll" type="fix">
        'TEST' was not set while compiling sources in testphase for coverage.
        Added setting of 'TEST' macro to the cover2:compile call.
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        New parameter for the run goal, allowing optional command line 
        parameters to be passed to the starting Erlang node.
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        Parameter in the package goal, controlling if the temporary directory is
        deleted or not.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, heyll" type="add">
        Added mock system (formerly known as ltest_mock, formerly known as
        erlymock). The system is automatically available for test modules during
        the test phase.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert, heyll" type="fix">
        Fixed various problems in test/compile phase when using include files
        from dependency applications.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="update">
        Changed dialyzer to run on sources not beams.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        New (fixed) surefire report generation handling each test module as
        separate test suite. Therefore an alternative surefire module is
        provided by the plugin.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added run goal for packaging erlang-otp to compile/test and run an
        erlang/OTP application for easy testing.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Release file generation and management support.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Application file generation and management support.
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        Added initial site documentation, generation of plugin-docs, changes
        and some development/contribution information.
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        New coverage report, replacing the old one. Now includes line-coverage
        with annotated source code listings.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="fix">
        Fixed cover compilation with the export_all option to provide coverage
        reports for non-exported module functions. Therefore an alternative,
        patched cover module is provided by the plugin.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added support for the maven-release-plugin by using application and
        release packaging variables in .app and .rel files.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added possibility to include non-erlang sources into application packages.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="fix">
        Fixed different problems with release packaging.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Changed erlang-otp packaging to .tar.gz internally.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Added several unit and integration tests.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Rewritten all mojos from the original maven-erlang plugin.
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Initial feature set: Compile project and test sources
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Initial feature set: Execute eunit tests
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Initial feature set: Execute dialyzer on erlang/OTP applications and
        releases
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Initial feature set: Generate site documentation with edoc for project
        and test code as well as surefire test reports and basic test code
        coverage
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Initial feature set: Package erlang/OTP applications
      </action>
      <action dev="schlagert" type="add">
        Initial feature set: Package erlang/OTP releases (consisting of
        erlang/OTP applications)
      </action>
      <action dev="olle-t" type="add">
        Initial feature set: Project setup-goal, with defaults for site and
        changelog, main sources and tests.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
